In the previous few videos,
Isa showed how to
build an application using
an LLM from evaluating
the inputs to processing
the inputs to then
doing final output checking
before you show the
output to the user.
After you've built such a system, how
do you know how it's working?
And maybe even as you deploy
it and let users use it,
how can you track how it's
doing and find any
shortcomings and continue to
improve the quality of
the answers of your system?
In this video, I'd like to share with
you some best practices
for evaluating the outputs
of an LLM and I want to share
with you specifically what
it feels like to build one of these
systems.
One key distinction
between what you hear me talk
about in this video and what
you may have seen in more
traditional machine learning
supervised learning applications
is because you can build such
an application so quickly,
the methods for evaluating it,
it tends not to start
off with a test set. Instead,
you often end up
gradually building up a
set of test examples.
Let me share with you
what I mean by that.
You may remember this
diagram from the second
video about how prompt-based
development speeds up
the core parts of model development
from maybe months
to just minutes or hours or
at most a very small number
of days.
In the traditional
supervised learning approach,
if you needed to collect say, 10,000
labeled examples anyway, then
the incremental cost of
collecting another 1,000 test
examples isn't that bad. So, in the
traditional supervised learning setting,
it was not
unusual to collect a
training set, collect a development
set or holdout
cross-validation set in the
test set and then
tap those at hand throughout this development process.
But if you're able to specify a prompt
in just minutes and get
something working in hours, then
it would seem like a
huge pain if you had
to pause for a long
time to collect 1,000 test
examples because you
cannot get this working with zero
training examples.
So, when building an
application using an LLM,
this is what it often feels like.
First, you would tune the
prompts on just a
small handful of examples,
maybe one to three to
five examples and try to
get a prompt that works on them.
And then as you have
the system undergo additional testing,
you occasionally run into a
few examples that are tricky.
The prompt doesn't
work on them or the algorithm doesn't work
on them.
And in that case, you can take these
additional one or two
or three or five
examples and add them
to the set that you're testing on to
just add additional
tricky examples opportunistically.
Eventually,
you have enough of these examples you've
added to your slowly growing development
set that it becomes a bit
inconvenient to manually
run every example
through the prompt
every time you change the prompt.
And then you start
to develop metrics to
measure performance on this
small set of examples,
such as maybe average accuracy.
And one interesting aspect
of this process is,
if you decide at any moment in time,
your system is working well enough,
you can stop right there and
not go on to the next bullet.
And in fact, there are many
deploy applications that
stops at maybe the first or
the second bullet and are running
actually just fine.
Now, if your hand-built
development set that you're evaluating
the model on isn't giving you
sufficient confidence yet in
the performance of your
system, then that's when
you may go to the next
step of collecting a randomly sampled set of
examples to tune the
model to.
And this would continue to be
a development set or a hold-out
cross-validation set, because it'd
be quite
common to continue to tune your
prompt to this.
And only if you need even
higher fidelity estimate
of the performance of your system,
then might you collect and use a hold-out
test sets that you don't even
look at yourself when you're tuning the
model. And so step
four tends to be more
important if, say, your system is
getting the right answer
91% of the time, and you want
to tune it to get
it to give the right
answer 92% or 93% of the time,
then you do need a larger
set of examples to measure those
differences between 91%
and 93% performance.
And then only if you really need an
unbiased, fair estimate of how
was the system doing,
then do you need to
go beyond the development set
to also collect a hold-out test set. One
important caveat, I've seen
a lot applications of
large language models where
there isn't meaningful meaning
risk of harm if
it gives not quite the right answer.
But obviously, for any high-stakes
applications, if there's a
risk of bias or
an inappropriate output causing
harm to someone, then the
responsibility to collect a
test set to rigorously
evaluate the performance of
your system to make
sure it's doing the right thing before you
use it, that becomes much
more important. But if, for
example, if you are
using it to summarize
articles just for yourself
to read and no
one else, then maybe the
risk of harm is more modest, and you
can stop early in this process without
going to the expense of bullets
four and five and collecting larger
data sets on which to evaluate
your algorithm.
So in this example,
let me start with
the usual helper functions.
Use the utils function
to get a list
of products and categories.
So,
in the computers and laptops category,
there's
a list of computers and laptops, in
the smartphones and
accessories category, here's a
list of smartphones and accessories, and so
on for other categories.
Now, let's say, the task we're going
to address is, given a
user input, such as, "what TV
can I buy if I'm on a
budget?", to retrieve the relevant categories and
products, so that we
have the right info to
answer the user's query.
So here's a prompt, feel
free to pause the video
and read through this in
detail if you wish. But
the prompt specifies a
set of instructions, and
it actually gives the
language model one example
of a good output. This
is sometimes called a few-shot or
technically one-shot prompting, because
we're actually using a
user message and a
system message to give
it one example of
a good output. If someone says, "I
want the most
expensive computer.". Yeah, let's just return
all the
computers, because we don't have pricing
information. Now, let's
use this prompt on the
customer message, "Which TV can
I buy if I'm
on a budget?".
And so we're
passing in to this both the prompt, customer
message zero, as
well as the products and category. This
is the information that
we have retrieved up
top using the utils function.
And here it lists out the
relevant information to this query,
which is under the category,
televisions and whole theater systems.
This is a list of TVs and whole
theater systems that seem relevant.
To see how well the prompt is doing,
you may evaluate it on a second prompt.
The customer says,
"I need a charger for my smartphone.".
It looks like it's
correctly retrieving this data.
Category, smartphones, accessories,
and it lists the relevant products.
And here's another one.
So, "What computers do you have?".
And hopefully you'll
retrieve a list of the computers.
So, here I have three prompts,
and if you are developing
this prompt for the first time,
it would be quite reasonable
to to have one or
two or three examples like this,
and to keep on
tuning the prompt until
it gives appropriate outputs,
until the prompt is retrieving the
relevant products and
categories to the
customer request for all of your
prompts,
all three of them in this example.
And if the prompt had been
missing some products or something,
then what we would
do is probably go back to edit the
prompt a few times until it gets it
right on all three of these prompts.
After you've
gotten the system to this point, you
might then start running
the system in testing. Maybe
send it to internal
test users or try
using it yourself, and
just run it for a
while to see what happens.
And sometimes you will run across
a prompt that it fails on. So here's
an example of a prompt, "tell
me about the smartx pro
phone and the fotosnap camera. Also,
what TVs do you have?".
So when I run it on this prompt,
it looks like it's
outputting the right data, but
it also outputs a bunch of text here,
this extra junk. It
makes it harder to
parse this into a Python list of dictionaries.
So we don't like that it's outputting
this extra junk. So when
you run across one
example that the system
fails on, then common
practice is to just note down
that this is a somewhat tricky
example, so let's add this
to our set of examples
that we're going to test
the system on systematically.
And if you keep on running
the system for a while longer,
maybe it works on those examples.
We did tune the
prompt to three examples,
so maybe it will work on many examples,
but just by chance you might
run across another example where it
generates an error.
So this custom message
for also causes the
system to output a
bunch of junk text at the end that
we don't want.
Trying to be helpful to
give all this extra text,
we actually don't want this.
And so at this point,
you may have run this prompt,
maybe on hundreds of examples,
maybe you have test users,
but you would just take the examples,
the tricky ones is doing poorly on,
and now I have this set of five
examples, index from 0 to 4,
have this set of
five examples that you
use to further fine-tune
the prompts.
And in both of these examples,
the LLM had output a
bunch of extra junk text
at the end that we don't want.
And after a little bit of trial and
error, you might decide to
modify the prompts as follows.
So here's a new prompt, this
is called prompt v2.
But what we did here
was we added to the prompt,
"Do not output any additional text that's
not in JSON format.", just
to emphasize, please don't output
this JSON stuff.
And added a second
example using the user
and assistant message for few-shot
prompting where the user asked for
the cheapest computer.
And in both of the few-shot
examples, we're demonstrating
to the system a
response where it gives
only JSON outputs. So here's the extra
thing that we just added
to the prompt, "Do not output
any additional text that's not in JSON
formats.", and we use "few_shot_user_1", "few_shot_assistant_1", and "few_shot_user_2",
"few_shot_assistant_2" to give it two of
these few shot prompts.
So let me hit Shift-Enter
to find that prompt.
And you were to go
back and manually rerun this
prompt on all five of
the examples of user inputs,
including this one
that previously had given a broken
output, you'll find that it now
gives a correct output. And
if you were to go back
and rerun this new prompt, this
is prompt version v2, on
that customer message
example that had results in the
broken output with extra junk after
the JSON output, then
this will generate a better output.
And I'm not going to do it here, but
I encourage you to
pause the video and
rerun it yourself on
customer message 4 as
well on this prompt v2, see
if it also generates
the correct output.
And hopefully it will,
I think it should.
And of course,
when you modify the prompts, it's
also useful to do a bit of regression
testing to make sure
that when fixing the
incorrect outputs on prompts
3 and 4, it didn't break
the output on prompt 0 either. Now, you
can kind of tell that if
I had to copy-paste 5 prompts,
customers such as
0, 1, 2, 3, and 4, into
my Jupyter notebook and run them
and then manually look
at them to see
if they output in the right categories and
products. You can kind
of do it. I can look
at this and go, "Yep, category, TV and
home
theater systems, products. Yep, looks
like you
got all of them.".
But it's actually a little bit painful
to do this manually, to
manually inspect or to
look at this output to make sure with
your eyes that this
is exactly the right output.
So when the development set that you're
tuning to becomes more
than just a small
handful of examples, it
then becomes useful to start to
automate the testing process.
So here is a set of 10 examples where I'm
specifying 10 customer messages. So
here's a customer message, "Which TV
can I buy if I'm on a
budget?" as well as what's the ideal answer.
Think of this as
the right answer in the
test set, or really, I should
say development
set, because we're actually tuning
to this.
And so we've collected here
10 examples indexed
from 0 through 9, where
the last one is if
the user says, "I would like hot tub time
machine.". We have no relevant products to
that, really sorry, so the ideal answer
is the
empty set.
And now,
if you want to evaluate automatically,
what the prompt is doing
on any of these 10 examples,
here is a function to do so. It's
kind of a long function. Feel
free to pause the
video and read through
it if you wish. But
let me just demonstrate what
it is actually doing.
So let me print
out the customer message,
for customer message 0.
So the customer message is,"Which
TV can I buy if I'm on
a budget?".
And let's
also print out the ideal answer. So
the ideal answer is here are all the
TVs that we want the prompt to retrieve.
And
let me now call the prompt. This
is prompt V2 on this customer
message with that
user products and
category information. Let's print
it out and then we'll call the
eval.
We'll call the eval response
of ideal function to
see how well the
response matches the ideal
answer.
And in this case, it did output the
category that we wanted,
and it did output
the entire list of products.
And so this gives it a score of 1.0.
Just to show you one more example,
it turns out that I know
it gets it wrong on example 7.
So if I change this from
0 to 7 and run it,
this is what it gets. Oh,
let me update this to 7 as well.
So under this customer message,
this is the ideal answer where
it should output
under gaming consoles
and accessories. So list of
gaming consoles and accessories.
But whereas the response
here has three outputs,
it actually should have had 1, 2, 3,
4, 5 outputs. And so it's
missing some of the products.
So what I would do if I'm
tuning the prompt now is I would then
use a fold to loop over all 10
of the development set examples, where
we repeatedly pull out
the customer message, get
the ideal answer, the
right answer, call
the arm to get a response, evaluate
it, and then, you know, accumulate
it in average. And
let me just run this.
So this will take a while to run,
but when it's done running, this
is the result. We're running
through the 10 examples. Looks like
example 7 was wrong. And so
the fraction correct of
10 was 90% correct.
And so,
if you were to tune the prompts,
you can rerun this to see if the
percent correct goes up or down.
What you just saw in this
notebook is going through steps 1,
2, and 3 of this bulleted list,
and this already gives a pretty
good development set of 10 examples
with which to tune and validate
the prompts is working.
If you needed an
additional level of rigor,
then you now have
the software needed to
collect a randomly sampled
set of maybe 100
examples with their ideal outputs,
and maybe even go beyond
that to the rigor of
a holdout test set that you don't
even look at while you're tuning
the prompt. But for
a lot of applications, stopping at
bullet 3, but there
are also certainly applications
where you could do
what you just saw me do in this
Jupyter notebook, and it
gets a pretty performance
system quite quickly.
With again,
the important caveat that if you're
working on a safety
critical application or an
application where there's non-trivial risk of
harm, then of course,
it would be the responsible thing to
do to actually get
a much larger test
set to really verify
the performance before you
use it anywhere.
And so that's it. I find that the
workflow of building
applications using prompts
is very different than a workflow
of building applications
using supervised learning,
and the pace of iteration
feels much faster. And
if you have not yet done it before, you
might be surprised at
how well an evaluation
method built on just
a few hand-curated tricky
examples. You think
with 10 examples, and this
is not statistically valid
for almost anything. But
you might be surprised
when you actually use this procedure,
how effective
adding a handful, just a
handful of tricky examples
into development sets might
be in terms of
helping you and your
team get to an
effective set of prompts
and effective system. In this
video, the outputs could be evaluated
quantitatively, as in
there was a desired
output and you could
tell if it gave
this desired output or not. So the
next video, let's take a
look at how you can evaluate output in
that setting where what
is the right answer
is a bit more
ambiguous.